But growing up as a child with the books around everywhere, with people to talk to about those books, this wasn't a sort of slightly learned thing. By the time I was 18, I had a deep passion for books. It wasn't the only passion I had. I was a South Indian brought up in Bengal. And two of the things about Bengal: they like their savory dishes and they like their sweets. So by the time I grew up, again, I had a well-established passion for food. Now I was growing up in the late '60s and early '70s, and there were a number of other passions I was also interested in, but these two were the ones that differentiated me. (Laughter) And then life was fine, dandy. Everything was okay, until I got to about the age of 26, and I went to a movie called "Short Circuit." Oh, some of you have seen it. And apparently it's being remade right now and it's going to be coming out next year. It's the story of this experimental robot which got electrocuted and found a life. And as it ran, this thing was saying, "Give me input. Give me input." And I suddenly realized that for a robot both information as well as food were the same thing. Energy came to it in some form or shape, data came to it in some form or shape. And I began to think, I wonder what it would be like to start imagining myself as if energy and information were the two things I had as input -- as if food and information were similar in some form or shape. I started doing some research then, and this was the 25-year journey, and started finding out that actually human beings as primates have far smaller stomachs than should be the size for our body weight and far larger brains. And as I went to research that even further, I got to a point where I discovered something called the expensive tissue hypothesis. That actually for a given body mass of a primate the metabolic rate was static. What changed was the balance of the tissues available. And two of the most expensive tissues in our human body are nervous tissue and digestive tissue. And what transpired was that people had put forward a hypothesis that was apparently coming up with some fabulous results by about 1995. It's a lady named Leslie Aiello. And the paper then suggested that you traded one for the other. If you wanted your brain for a particular body mass to be large, you had to live with a smaller gut. That then set me off completely to say, Okay, these two are connected. So I looked at the cultivation of information as if it were food and said, So we were hunter-gathers of information. We moved from that to becoming farmers and cultivators of information. Does that really explain what we're seeing with the intellectual property battles nowadays? Because those people who were hunter-gatherers in origin wanted to be free and roam and pick up information as they wanted, and those that were in the business of farming information wanted to build fences around it, create ownership and wealth and structure and settlement. So there was always going to be a tension within that. And everything I saw in the cultivation said there were huge fights amongst the foodies between the cultivators and the hunter-gatherers. And this is happening here. When I moved to preparation, this same thing was true, expect that there were two schools. One group of people said you can distill your information, you can extract value, separate it and serve it up, while another group turned around and said no, no you can ferment it. You bring it all together and mash it up and the value emerges that way. The same is again true with information. But consumption was where it started getting really enjoyable. Because what I began to see then was there were so many different ways people would consume this. They'd buy it from the shop as raw ingredients. Do you cook it? Do you have it served to you? Do you go to a restaurant? The same is true every time as I started thinking about information. The analogies were getting crazy -- that information had sell-by dates, that people had misused information that wasn't dated properly and could really make an effect on the stock market, on corporate values, etc. And by this time I was hooked. And this is about 23 years into this process. And I began to start thinking of myself as we start having mash-ups of fact and fiction, docu-dramas, mockumentaries, whatever you call it. Are we going to reach the stage where information has a percentage for fact associated with it? We start labeling information for the fact percentage? Are we going to start looking at what happens when your information source is turned off, as a famine? Which brings me to the final element of this. Clay Shirky once stated that there is no such animal as information overload, there is only filter failure. I put it to you that information, if viewed from the point of food, is never a production issue; you never speak of food overload. Fundamentally it's a consumption issue. And we have to start thinking about how we create diets within ourselves, exercise within ourselves, to have the faculties to be able to deal with information, to have the labeling to be able to do it responsibly. In fact, when I saw "Supersize Me," I starting thinking of saying, What would happen if an individual had 31 days nonstop Fox News? (Laughter) Would there be time to be able to work with it? So you start really understanding that you can have diseases, toxins, a need to balance your diet, and once you start looking, and from that point on, everything I have done in terms of the consumption of information, the production of information, the preparation of information, I've looked at from the viewpoint of food. It has probably not helped my waistline any because I like practicing on both sides. But I'd like to leave you with just that question: If you began to think of all the information that you consume the way you think of food, what would you do differently? Thank you very much for your time. (Applause)
Sin embargo, crecer rodeado de libros y con gente que hablaba de esos libros, no fue un aprendizaje sencillo. A los 18 años, había desarrollado una profunda pasión por los libros. No era la única pasión que tenía. Nací en el sur de la India, pero crecí en Bengala. Bengala tiene 2 características: los platos sabrosos y los dulces. Así que a medida que crecía, desarrollaba también una gran pasión por la comida. Mi juventud transcurrió entre fines de los años 60 y principios de los 70 también tenía otras pasiones, pero estas dos eran las que me diferenciaban. (Risas) Y entonces la vida era buena, excelente. Todo iba bien hasta que cumplí 26 años y vi la película “Cortocircuito”. ¡Oh!, algunos de ustedes la han visto. Y parece que están haciendo una nueva versión para el próximo año. Es la historia de este robot experimental que se electrocutó y cobró vida. Y cuando corría, decía: “Aliméntame, aliméntame”. Y de repente me di cuenta de que para un robot información y alimento eran lo mismo. Se cargaba de energía de alguna forma y los datos ingresaban de alguna manera. Y me puse a pensar, me pregunté cómo sería si me imaginase a mí mismo con la energía y la información como dos entradas, como si la comida y la información tuviesen formas similares. Empecé a investigar y esto resultó ser un viaje de 25 años en el que descubrí que los seres humanos, en tanto primates, tenemos estómagos mucho más pequeños de lo que deberíamos, dado nuestro peso corporal, y cerebros mucho más grandes. Y a medida que investigaba más, llegué a un punto en el que descubrí algo llamado la hipótesis del tejido costoso que propone que la tasa metabólica de la determinada masa corporal de un primate es estática. Lo que cambia es el equilibrio de los tejidos disponibles. Y dos de los tejidos más costosos del cuerpo humano son los del sistema nervioso y del digestivo. Y ocurrió que la persona que había propuesto esta hipótesis, que al parecer tuvo grandes resultados alrededor de 1995, era una mujer llamada Leslie Aiello. El documento sugería que eran intercambiables. Si alguien quería que su cerebro tuviese mayor tamaño, tenía que vivir con un tubo digestivo más pequeño. Me resultó muy provocador aceptar esta interconexión. Entonces, vi el cultivo de información como si se tratase de comida; habíamos sido cazadores-recolectores de información. Luego nos convertimos en agricultores y cultivamos información. ¿Esto podría explicar lo que estamos viendo con las batallas de propiedad intelectual hoy en día? Debido a que estos eran originalmente cazadores- recolectores, querían ser libres, errar y recoger la información que querían, y los que cultivaban información querían cercarla, crear propiedad, riqueza, estructura y asentamientos. Así que siempre iba a haber tensión. Y vi que en los cultivos había grandes peleas entre los amantes de la comida entre los agricultores y los cazadores-recolectores. Y esto está ocurriendo aquí. Cuando pasé a la preparación, ocurrió lo mismo, excepto que había 2 escuelas. Un grupo de personas decía que la información podía extraerse, extraerse valor, separarlo y servirlo, mientras que el otro grupo decía que no, que se podía fermentar. El valor surge si se tiene todo junto, consolidado. Lo mismo ocurre con la información. Sin embargo, todo se vuelve agradable con el consumo porque entonces me di cuenta de que había muchas maneras diferentes de consumo. Se compra materia prima en la tienda. ¿Ustedes cocinan? ¿Quieren que los sirvan? ¿Van a un restaurante? Lo mismo ocurre cuando pienso en la información. Las analogías eran sorprendentes: la información tiene fecha de caducidad, pero hay gente que hace mal uso de la información que no estaba fechada correctamente y eso puede repercutir en el mercado de valores, en los valores corporativos, etc. Y en ese momento estaba cautivado. Y este proceso lleva cerca de 23 años. Empecé a pensar en mí mismo a medida que la gente empieza a confundir la realidad y la ficción: docudramas, documentales falsos, como quieran llamarlo. ¿Llegaremos a un punto en que la información tenga un porcentaje de realidad? ¿Llegaremos a etiquetar la información de acuerdo a ese porcentaje de realidad? ¿Veremos qué sucede cuando la fuente de información se apague, como en una hambruna? Esto me lleva al último elemento. Clay Shirky dijo una vez que no existe la sobrecarga de información, solo hay fallas en el filtraje. Si vemos la información desde el punto de vista de la comida, nunca hay problemas de producción, nunca se habla de sobrecarga de alimentos. Se trata fundamentalmente de un problema de consumo. Y tenemos que pensar cómo hacer dietas y ejercitarnos para tener las facultades para enfrentar la información, para que el etiquetado se haga de manera responsable. De hecho, cuando vi “Súper engórdame”, empecé a pensar ¿qué pasaría si alguien pasase 31 días ininterrumpidos con noticias de la cadena Fox? (Risas) ¿Habría tiempo para procesar eso? Así que empezamos a comprender que podemos tener enfermedades y toxinas y que necesitamos equilibrar nuestra dieta y una vez que buscamos, a partir de ese momento, todo lo que he hecho en términos de consumo, producción y preparación de la información, todo lo he considerado desde el punto de vista de los alimentos. Probablemente esto no ha ayudado en nada a mi silueta porque me gusta practicar en ambos lados. Pero me gustaría dejarles esta pregunta: Si consideramos toda la información que consumimos como si se tratase de alimentos, ¿qué cambiaríamos? Muchas gracias por su tiempo. (Aplausos)